<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Just rebuke of a late unmannerly libel in defence of the court entituled Cursory remarks upon some late disloyal proceedings &amp;c.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 33 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 12 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A46386</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11314500</idno>
  <idno type="VID">47428</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240862006</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing J1237</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R30426</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">11314500</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A46386)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 47428)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1465:6)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Just rebuke of a late unmannerly libel in defence of the court entituled Cursory remarks upon some late disloyal proceedings &amp;c.</title>
                  <author>Jurieu, Pierre, 1637-1713.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>21 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London printed :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Sometimes attributed to Pierre Jurieu.</note>
                  <note>In double columns.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1660-1714.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-06 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:47428:1"/>
            <p>A JUST REBUKE Of a late Unmannerly LIBEL, IN Defence of the COURT: ENTITULED, <hi>Cursory Remarks upon some late Disloyal Proceedings,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed in the Year, 1699.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="treatise">
            <pb facs="tcp:47428:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:47428:2"/>
            <head>A JUST REBUKE Of a late unmannerly Libel, in Defence of the Court: ENTITULED, <hi>Cursory Remarks upon some late Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loyal Proceedings,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THE Author that has troubled the World with those <hi>Cursory Remarks,</hi> that you are pleas'd to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sire my Opinion of, is inge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niously hinted at in yours, and saves me the expence of time, in making a <hi>Gazette</hi> Description of his Person or Employment. I am of your Perswasion also, that he labours under the same Disease, that he makes o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Men infected with, <hi>viz. The want of an Office to keep his Coach on the Wheels, and his two black Steeds from the Dog Kennel.</hi> At the begin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning of the War he wrote himself into a Coach, and a Post of Three Hundred Pounds a Year; and the Peace being like to deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine that Reward, he is
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:47428:3"/>Angling for another, by the successful Methods of <hi>Flat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering the Court, and Abusing true English-men, under the Name of</hi> Pseudo Patriots, the never failing Topicks to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance sordid Parasites; but since I am of Opinion, that he will once more be brought upon his Marrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bones to make his Recanta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and pray Absolution in St. <hi>Stephen</hi>'s Chapel; or else having serv'd the Court to his own Ruin, they will lay him aside, and expose him to their last Rewards of Want and Beggary, as they have done by all the rest of their Scriblers; I shall make no addition to his Misery, by reflecting on his Conduct, but leave him to be punish'd by the Idols he has Worshipp'd, that the Sense of his own Folly, in fawning upon an Ungrate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Court, may reduce him to Reason, and teach o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers from his Rueful Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ample, that Men always a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bandon themselves, when they Desert the Interest of their Country, to support a Medley that know Men no longer, than they are the Cats Feet in the Monkey's hands, and burn their own Fingers to procure Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges for those that hugg'd them into Ruine; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore leaving the Author to the Fate of his Brethren, I shall proceed to examine his <hi>Remarks.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Which he begins in the common Dialect of all Court Flatterers, by in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veighing bitterly against feigned Fears and Dangers, and perswading Obedience to Authority, as a Christian Duty; which, in the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sign of Parasites, and Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der-proppers of the Court, is nothing but advancing Absolute Authority, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroying Co-ordinate Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:47428:3"/>reducing Freemen un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Yoke of <hi>Will</hi> and <hi>Pleasure;</hi> Playing the Old Game at Noddy o're again, setting up the exploded Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctrine of Passive Obedience, <gap reason="illegible: in gutter" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>ew vampimg <hi>Hodge</hi>'s Old Observators, Copying after Bp. <hi>B</hi>— Dr. <hi>Sh—k,</hi> Dr. H—<hi>s,</hi> and <hi>Heraclitus Ridens,</hi> and they want nothing but a King to countenance the Tory Project.</p>
            <p>Having laid this Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation for an Arbitrary Stru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture in Page 3d. 4th. and 5th. he gives us a clawing Account <hi>of the Great and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>valuable Blessings that the King has Conferr'd upon us, in deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vering us from Popery and Sla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very:</hi> In which he might have spared his pains, for is we are more sensible of it man of any the Tory party, so we are more truly thank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful for it, than those that serve the Government be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cause it serves them. We have already, in requital, given the King all we have to give. All the Rights of an <hi>English</hi> King, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And tho' the <hi>Cursory Sir Roger</hi> in his fulsom Panegyricks, says <hi>The King has Deserv'd more than</hi> England <hi>has to Give;</hi> yet we must be excused, that we dont Compliment away our Liberty also, for that is not ours to give, and hope it will never be in the power of any sort of Men to take it from us, under pretence of Loyalty and Duty, and give it to the King, that we are sure does not desire more than he has already; for those are the worst of his Enemies, that by making him greater than he ought to be, would make him no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing at all in the esteem of his People.</p>
            <p>Page the Sixth and Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venth, the <hi>Cursory Remarker</hi> gratifies his Spleen, <hi>in Rank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Common Wealth Party
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:47428:4"/>with the Jacobites, and setting them up as United Enemies a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the Government;</hi> which is so great a Contradiction, that nothing but a servile Drudge to the Court, and Absolute Authority, could be guilty of. The Instan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces he gives to prove his un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warrantable Assumptions, are as weak as ridiculous; for to make a Jacobite a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>publican, or a Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth's Man a Jacobite, to use his own words upon a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother occasion, <hi>is as great an Impossibility as to reconcile disagreeing Elements, or whi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten the Skin of an</hi> Aethiopian. But I suppose the Author's pique is not against their Persons, but their Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples; and therefore Reviles the Works of the Honour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able Mr. <hi>Sidney,</hi> the judici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Mr. <hi>Ludlow,</hi> and the unanswerable Mr. <hi>Harring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton</hi> and Mr. <hi>Milton:</hi> And I hope, Sir, his Masters will Condemn him to the Pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nishment of answering those Elaborate Discourses of Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, and the Liberties and Priviledges of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject, for then he'l undergo the Fate of <hi>Salmasius,</hi> and the Government will save the charge of keeping up his Coach, there being enough of Mr. <hi>Milton</hi>'s Scholars left to Vindicate that Noble cause, till they have Writ him to Death, as their Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor did <hi>Salmasius.</hi> In Page the Eighth, his Character of a Patriot is very particular, and obliging; for, he says, <hi>'tis to be always against the Court,</hi> and so every Honest Man ought to be, till they Reform, or Hands are chang'd for a better Admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistration, which yet I don't despair of, because I think it possible for a Good King to mend Mal-contrivances, tho' not easy for a Nation, so soon to return to that
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:47428:4"/>Power, which has cost three Kingdoms so much Blood and Treasure to throw off.</p>
            <p>In page the Ninth, our <hi>Remarker</hi> seems very much grieved, that Men of Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity, and Consideration, should not be all born blind, and without Sense, of the Miseries the Community la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour under from the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sent Administration; but let him afflict himself as he will, good Men of all Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lities will be apt to talk, and sometimes give those Men hard Words, that they see take such pains to deserve them, from which all our <hi>Remarker's</hi> Oratory cannot Defend or Absolve them; for by vertue of an old <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lish</hi> Adage, <hi>Loosers have al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways Leave to speak; and he that's pinch'd hard will com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain, tho' the hand be never so sacred that made him smart.</hi> Nor must private Persons escape the lash of our Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor's scurrilous Pen; but to shew he fights a Battle Royal, he strikes all that stand near him, ready to oppose his Arbitrary Noti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, and would gag the mouths of all Mankind, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the Soldiery, whom he flatters for a Reason that cost their Disbanding, and which, in time, he must think to account for.</p>
            <p>The Author's Praemoni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion (as he calls it) being brought to a conclusion, he delivers himself of a won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derful Discovery, without one word of truth in the whole, viz. <hi>That there is a Union and Confederacy between the Old Jacobites, Republicans, Malcontented Murmurrers, and New Converts, to overthrow the Government.</hi> This Confede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racy our Court Regrator calls the <hi>Mixture,</hi> and so treats them with all the u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sual Expressions of the Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preme
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:47428:5"/>Court of <hi>England,</hi> that its no hard task to find out whom he means by the <hi>Members of Clubs and Cabals against the Government;</hi> but I shall not anticipate a <hi>Meli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us Inquirendum,</hi> nor pretend to know his thoughts, since the Province he has under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taken, in defending a Court that the whole Common-Wealth is sick and weary of, sufficiently assure me he can have no good Intention to the Community, in sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>porting a Medley that are contriving its Ruine; as is apparently demonstrated in page 15, 16 and 17, which he wholly employs in curb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, restraining and damn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Power and Privile<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges of the People, and mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifying Monarchical Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority, equal, if not, su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periour, to the Power of God Almighty. What a Monster in Government does he make of the Power of the People, which we have so long Sweat, purg'd and Bled for? How con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>temptibly does he Redicult that memorable Saying, which is the Glory of this Age, and will be the Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity of all that shall succeed it, viz. <hi>Did not we make him King,</hi> insinuating, that <hi>We gave away a Power we could not, nor ought not to keep, not knew how to manage:</hi> Nay, that there was no Thanks due for a Donative of Three Kingdoms, but <hi>that we were Obliged to his Majesty for Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepting it as a Debt due for our Deliverance and Protection:</hi> Tho' the Villany of this Romantick Assertion is ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sily exploded, by consult<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Terms on which the Trust was surrendred, and in his Fathering the Power of Disposing Crowns upon God Almighty, that the King might seem under no Obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gation to the People.</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:47428:5"/>
            <p> Censuring the proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings of the Court he calls a <hi>Scandalous Crime,</hi> page the Nineteenth, and pronoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceth a <hi>Woe</hi> against it in his Preface; but forgets the Scandal is given by the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters, and consequently that he denounceth the Curse against his Masters, <hi>by whom our Offences come.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>The Liberty of the Subject he Treats as a Fiction, a Chimera, the Imposition of cuning Knaves upon Credulous Fools, and tells us there is no such thing in the World,</hi> page the 20th and 21th, and that the pretence of Liberty, <hi>was but alluring Subjects from their Allegiance to the King, to conciliate them to the Tyranny of the Senate:</hi> And thus by shifting the Scene, excusing the Male<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factors, and condemning the Innocent as Malecontents, are we brought upon the Ridge of a Precipice, in ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pectation that our Enemies, will some time or other be so kind, to cast us down Head long, and free us from worser things that are coming up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on us; for what true <hi>English</hi> man had not rather loose his Life than his Liberty, and entail a Vassalage upon his Posterity. The Enemies of Liberty, if they please, may still say <hi>our Fears are foolish;</hi> but there is no truer Symptom of the utter loss of that glorious Privelege, than advancing the power of the the Monarchy beyond its Limitted proportion. For tho whilst men are declaim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing against the Sin of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellion, they commonly tell us 'tis better to suffer than to Sin; yet we should e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>qually take care, that our suffering foolishly be not a greater Sin, than opposing the methods of our Ruin. Power, its true, is of <hi>a Divine Original,</hi> but the Exercise of power is too often in the
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:47428:6"/>hands of such immoral Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, as tempt Men to say, they have no Souls that are kin to God Almighty; but are the Instruments and A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gents of the Prince of Dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness. Thanks be to Heaven, we have a good King, that knows himself and his In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terest; yet Men should take care they don't indeavour by straining the points of Prerogative and Obedience, lead him into Temptation; and therefore I cannot but commend the Doctor, fam'd for Learning and Piety, quo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted in Answer to a Letter, relating to the present Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistry, that deliver'd him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self in a great Congregation in these Words. It is too often the Fault of Learned Men to flatter Princes; and we find the Translators of our Bible guilty in this mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, or they would not so grossly have Erred in that, where they Translate, <hi>who saith to a King thou art wicked;</hi> whereas in the Hebrew, it is, <hi>thou shalt say to a King, thou art wicked;</hi> that is, said the Doctor, if he be so, he should be told of it; and this, Sir, would lead any Man of less modesty, than him that covets to be thought worthy of your Friendship, into indecent Railery against our <hi>Cursory Remarker,</hi> for Flattering his Prince, and Defending ill Ministers that make ill times, and covering ill times, which continue and increase ill Ministers, which is our present Calamity.</p>
            <p>In Page the 22th, he Raves against an Intermix<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of Interests against the Government, as if he were distracted, and had wholy mistaken his Hypothesis; for what he employs as arguments in behalf of the Ministry, is totally against them. A Single Interest
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:47428:6"/>might be corrupted or bias<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed by false Principles; but where all Interests agree, and speak the same things, of ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessity they must be true, and the Persons accused must be guilty. In such a Case, the general Voice of the People must be esteem'd as the Voice of God. Nor is bringing the King in as a Party, or setting up an <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termixture of Interest</hi> as Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies to his Majesty, any ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuse for the Mismanage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Abuses commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by his Ministers, for ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny a good Master may have ill Servants, and 'tis the King's misfortune to have too many, who have such Tricks in keeping Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints from his eares, and representing the Persons griev'd as professed Enemies to his Royalty, that 'tis al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>most impossible for any Complaints to reach him, but under such prejudices, as utterly destroy the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portance and Weight of the matter complain'd of; and by these nefarious Arts and Shifts the Ministry maintain their own Reputations with the King, and stifle all Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaints against them; which if his Majesty was acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted with, he would no more keep such Men about him, than he would warm a Snake in his Bosom. We are now under a Distemper that was never heard of before in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land.</hi> All for the King, and none for the Ministers, and it will be the wonder of A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges to come, as it is the Tor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of this, to see our selves ruined by a few Men, that have no Interest or pan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty in the Nation; of whom a pleasant Gentleman said the other day, <hi>That one Wher<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry would carry away all the King's Friends in the Ministry, if they were separated from their Employments.</hi> And there may
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:47428:7"/>be reason to believe it, if we again consider their poli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticks, which shows them to be at their last shifts, and like <hi>Teague,</hi> who running too fast in a Race, had no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing to excuse his Faults, but that he run away with himself. So our Author's way of justifying the Court is to criminate the whole Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. When the Church Party complain they are Jacobites. When the Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>senters complain they are Common Wealths Men; but this Disguise will e're long drop off, and things will appear as they are, to the shame and confusion of the Agressors and Main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainers.</p>
            <p>The generality of Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple that complain of Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances, love their Houses well, tho' they do not Ride upon the Ridge of them, and have a greater respect for the King, than those that seem so much concerned for his Prerogative and Honour. We blame not the King, tho' we are called Muti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neers, if we speak but one Semi-Vowel against the Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters, for from Him only we expect Abuses will be remedied, who is not con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd in their Guilt. The King came in a Stranger a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong us, and was under a necessity of employing those whom he found in the Bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>siness of the State, and from such Plants as had been rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed in the corrupt Soil of the late Reigns, no very good Fruit could be expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted; and as their oppor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunities for Frauds were greater than any former Age ever produced, so they have made the best use of their Advantages, to cram their own Coffers by exhausting the Nation's Treasure.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Clubs</hi> and <hi>Cabals</hi> that the <hi>Cursory Remarker</hi> so base<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:47428:7"/>spits his Venom at, are known to be composed of Men of great parts and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tegrity; and <hi>that they influence Superior Classes</hi> (which he u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses as fine Words, to cover a foul meaning) is an Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of their Probity, not of their Disparagement, tho' he suborns it to that wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed purpose; and whether they love and serve the King or not, may be better Read in the <hi>Encomiums</hi> they give him, than in the sordid Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flections this Court Flatte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter is pleas'd to make upon their ingenious and honest productions? For let him writh and stretch that inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent Expression as far as he pleases, to make it speak his own ill intended Sense, 'tis no Disparagement to any mortal King, to say he is not fit to be trusted with what an Immortal Angel is not qualified for.</p>
            <p>Those bantering Dogge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ril Rhimes, the <hi>Remarker</hi> has borrowed from a late bold <hi>Encomiaster,</hi> and those he has added of his own, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern not those he is pleas'd to call <hi>Clubbers,</hi> but fly at a Nobler Game; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore shall be answer'd when we draw towards a Conclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion. And for the story of the King of <hi>Ceilon,</hi> which <hi>he Redicules as a poor crawling Fancey, Ridiculous in its appli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, and unpardonable for its Wit,</hi> has more genuine Sense, and honest meaning in it, than can be found in all his Sixty six pages; and will not be lessen'd by a Fool's Laughing at what he wont understand.</p>
            <p>What Ridiculous Drol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lery does he make <hi>page</hi> 29, about a very serious Questi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, <hi>The Power of the Sword,</hi> but in that he may be excu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed, for being unable to Answer the Position by
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:47428:8"/>Arguments <hi>ad Rem,</hi> he has the Confidence to divert his Reader, by laughing at all Perswasions, but that of the Church of <hi>England,</hi> who, he knows, if they had a Sword to give, would not fail to put it into the hands of any Monarch, that would sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port their Ecclesiastical Ty<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ranny. <hi>Page</hi> 30. he quarrels with the Pamphlet called <hi>Considerations upon the State of the Navy;</hi> and, pray Sir, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sider what has enraged his Spleen? Why, it is, that those that are at the Charge should superintend the Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fair, which all Men of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Sense will think so rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonable and Natural, that it cannot be denied or dispu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted; and yet this doughty <hi>Court Tool,</hi> that can see no mismanagement in the Court, has almost found out High Treason in that Sentence, and calls it <hi>Lurching from the King to bestow it upon the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament; Invading the King's Prerogative,</hi> and a thousand other <hi>Mormo's,</hi> that might Bugbear the Commons of <hi>England</hi> from Redressing En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ormities in the Administra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</p>
            <p>The last position you set Sir, put our Author into a mighty Ferment; but what follows has made him boyl over in Froth and Folly, <hi>viz.</hi> That Kings are accountable to their Subjects, and that upon Fore falture of their own free will and Power, they may proceed to a New Election, and place one more Righteous upon the Throne. This he calls, <hi>Opening a Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gical Schene, subverting the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, spotting people with the Plague of Rebellion,</hi> and many other pretty Epithets that his Fancy abounds with, which, in effect, is but arraigning the Proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings of the Honorable Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventional Parliaments, in
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:47428:8"/>the case of the late King <hi>James</hi> the Second, to whom I refer him for a further answer.</p>
            <p>Having loaded the Worthy Gentlemen that he is pleas'd to call the <hi>Mixture,</hi> and <hi>Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditious Interpositors</hi> with <hi>New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate</hi> Metephors, <hi>and running into Eternal Circulations of Feigning Fears and Jealousies, to Slander the Government;</hi> he proceeds to assign the Causes of all these Misdemeanors in the <hi>Mixture,</hi> but first re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires positive proofs a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the Ministry, that they are guilty of misma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagements, and enriching themselves by Plundering the Nation, or else he says, <hi>all their Accusations like Sir</hi> H. D. C—It's <hi>Petition, will be look'd upon as Ridiculous, Vex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>atious, and Scandalous.</hi> I won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der in what Cell the Author spends his time, that can find so many Egregious Faults among the <hi>Clubbers,</hi> and none among the Cour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiers; but there are no sort of Men so blind, as those that will not see, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore if he has a Mind to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form himself, let him en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire at the Admiralty Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice, why the <hi>Toloun</hi> Fleet was suffered to enter their Port, and our Fleet appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Stations that they might be sure to miss them, or be kept in their Harbours for want of Sailing Orders, till the <hi>French</hi> were arrived in Safety. He may also, if his Leisure from Writing for the Government will permit him, enquire after the es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cape of <hi>Ponti</hi>'s Squadron, and the causes of so many Merchants being ruin'd, by losing their Ships in the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Chops of the Channel, for want of Cruisers. From thence he may walk to the Victualling Office, and es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecially to that Stye of Fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy Swine the Navy Office,
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:47428:9"/>who wallow in the Myre of their own Wealth and Wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>edness, and share the whole Office and profits, almost in one Family and Kindred. Here he may find the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Controler, one Son a Receiver, another Payma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ster, a near Kinsman Cheque upon the Rest, and then there is like you'l say, to be very <hi>Saving doings</hi> for the Publick. From thence he may return to <hi>White-hall;</hi> the Offices at the Horse-Guards, and those in St. <hi>James</hi>'s Park, and if he find in any one Barrel, better Herring than the rest, he will have greater luck than all the World beside. Here as 'tis printed by honest Mr. <hi>Darby,</hi> he may find the spoil so great, that a Sweeper of an Office of twenty pounds <hi>per annum</hi> stipend, has in four years time arrived to an Estate of Six Thousand Pounds! and Clerks in Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices of Eighty pounds a Year Salary, that have pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chased Twenty Thousand pounds Sterling: And in this proportion its said to go generally through all the Offices in the Kingdom; and this management is laid with so great Judgment, that the Quallifications of a Person for an Imployment, is to have good Testimonals, that he understands the World; a soft Character for a Knave; and now I hope our Remarker will not com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain for want of proof a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst the Managers.</p>
            <p>Another shift to support his Masters Credits, shews all Complainants <hi>as Men that want Places, and therefore Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vile and Slaunder the present Ministry, in hopes to make Room for themselves.</hi> And possibly there may be some such Men in the World, but they are none of those we desire should have Offices; but
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:47428:9"/>such only, as are duly qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lified in respect of their Parts and Principle for the Service of the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>weal; that have in both the late Reigns distinguish'd themselves to be solely in the Interest of their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, and lye under no temp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation by the meanness of their Circumstances, to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rich themselves by Ruining the Nation; of which his Majesty has greater choice than any Prince in <hi>Europe,</hi> and can never change so of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten, but a supply will in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crease on his hands, till his number is compleated with Men fearing God, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting Covetousness; which are now as rare to be found at Court, as a <hi>Phaenix</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> which was never heard of, but in the Deserts of <hi>Arabia.</hi> In the mean time His Majesty is very safe in making Alterations, till he is blest with such a Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nistry as is above described; because 'tis impossible to find worse than he has al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready. He has began that good work, but still one thing seems not only necessa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, but in order to a thorow Reformation of Absolute Necessity, and that is, to cleans all his Offices so per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectly, as not to leave one Soul in them, that may Taint, or Mislead the New ones, into the old. Track of Ignorance, Infidelity, or Deceit, which I know, Sir, would be a great Satis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction to your self, and to all true Hearted <hi>English</hi> Men.</p>
            <p>Our <hi>Remarker's</hi> next De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sign is, to perswade the World that Disbanding the Army, <hi>was to expose the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to Eminent danger,</hi> but it's easy to be perceived, that under that pretence he is only Flattering the Author of the <hi>Ballancing-Letter,</hi>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:47428:10"/>who being in a mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney Post, might consider and Reward it as a Service to the Government, as he did the Author of <hi>King Arthur,</hi> for assisting His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty's Enemies with such Arguments against his Title, as neither the <hi>Balancer</hi> nor the Poetical Medicastrian Knight, will ever be able to Answer or attone for. And the Remarkers saying, the Quiet of His Majesties Subjects prevail'd upon his Judgment, is a bolder ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>position on the Text than the Original will allow; for if His Majesty had not been absolutely of opinion, That the Bill was reason<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able, and the end of it for the Advantage of his People, he would never have given it the Royal Assent, for we allow what the Author says in another place, that <hi>He is not to be Hector'd into a Compliance against his Judgment;</hi> but the Work is done, and a Glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious thing it was on both sides.</p>
            <q>
               <l>If we for fear of such Alarms,</l>
               <l>Had kept up Standing Forces,</l>
               <l>It had been well for those in Arms,</l>
               <l>But ill for Country <hi>Inns</hi> and <hi>Farms,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To 've kept both Men and Horses.</l>
            </q>
            <p>Liberty and Property, Freedom of Speech, and not fearing the Face of Men in the cause of our Country, are great Motes in the Eyes of this <hi>Pedantick Scribler;</hi> and he has no way to rub them out, and clear his Eye Sight for the ampler Vin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dication of his Pay-masters, but by scandalizing the brave Asserters of our Priveleges,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:47428:10"/>as a Pack of <hi>Factious and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poverish'd Intermedlers, that are striving to enrich themselves, by shouldering into Offices, and Places of Trust and Profit;</hi> whereas he wholy mistakes the Case, for the pretence that other men are their <hi>Rivals,</hi> and would jostle them out of Favour and Authority, are but the Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifices of the Courtiers, to keep what they have en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gross'd; and seeing them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves attack'd like common Criminals, cry out with the Mob, <hi>Stop 'em, Stop 'em,</hi> as if others, and not themselves were the Malefactors, when the Noise is only rais'd to divert the Pursuers, while the true Offenders may e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>scape Apprehending, and being brought to Justice. This has been of great Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice to our Mismanagers hitherto; but to use his own Words, <hi>The cunning will not always be Crown'd with success.</hi> A Day of Reck<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oning is coming, and then it will appear, that the <hi>Balance</hi> was not held in up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>right hands, nor the Court, nor depending Offices, the honestest places in <hi>Christen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom;</hi> and therefore no Crime to seek an Imploy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, if there were no o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Reason for it, than to disposess those that have ill treated us too long al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Ambition, Envy, Pride, and Vanity,</hi> which the <hi>Mercenary Remarker</hi> complains of a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong Mal-contents, and Place-mongers, are the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pidemical Diseases of the Court, and he should first have attempted upon the Irregular Constitution of his Patrons, before he had posted up his Bills for the Cure of other people of the Real Fears, and Jealousies, that an Extravagant ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nagement has brought us
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:47428:11"/>under. How like Children do they treat us, and as if the Foolishest of angry Old Women had been their Teachers, they beat us till we are forc'd to complain; beat us for complaining, and then stop our Mouths, that our Injuries and their Injustice might be conceal'd from such as would Pity and Relieve us. They call us Ambitious, because we desire they should be ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nest: Envious, because we desire Abuses should be Rectified: Proud, because we can't lye still when we are trampled on: And Vain, because we can't fall in Love with Slavery, and become Vassals to a set of as Vain, Proud, Envious, and Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitious, Self-conceited Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>micks, as <hi>England</hi> e're pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duc'd, or honest Men were plagu'd with.</p>
            <p>Excluding Members that having Offices at Court, of Trust and Profit, the House of Commons may not think fit to serve in that Honourable Station, he says, <hi>looks with a very Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>britary Countenance upon all the Gentry of</hi> England, <hi>and Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raigns their Justice, and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tegrity, to think an Officer can Corrupt or Biass them from their Duty and Affection to their Country.</hi> This is a Right Court Turn, and such as was never Intended by the Author of Considerations upon the choice <hi>of a Speaker,</hi> which he Mistakes for a Confutation of the <hi>Ballan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cing-Letter;</hi> who Urges it as an Argument against a great Minister, being made Speaker of the House of Commons, and says, 'tis natural to believe, he will use the same Arts to keep his Office, as he did to get
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:47428:11"/>it: And if it be considered, how several Members of our late Parliaments, got into the most Advanta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gious places of profit; whom the Court would not have seen, nor the Country felt, had they not been first Members; it must be granted, that they were advanced, not by serving the Nation, but the Court, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ought to be kept out for the Future; and tho' our Remarker Rails hear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tily <hi>against supposing there are Parties, and Factions in the House of Commons;</hi> yet the Author of the Considera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions aforesaid, tells you this Distinction of <hi>Court and Country Party</hi> there, is not groundless or ill meant: For if ever a Parliament was without such a Distinction, it was when a Court was without such Ministers; who instead of serving the Government, serve them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves upon it, at the ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence of their Masters Hon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our, and by impoverish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their Country; and therefore the Distinction is necessary, and must pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>serve the Honour of our Antient Constituton of Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, 'till it may flou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rish under the Influence of a Parliament; in which, none, or few, who have gainful Offices, shall be Members of the House of Commons; and a Bill to that purpose was accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ingly preferr'd, and if it wants effect, it is the <hi>Lords</hi> doing, and wonderful in our Eyes.</p>
            <p>Sending home the <hi>Dutch</hi> Guards, he calls an Act of <hi>Heinous ingratitude, and Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>honourable to the Nation,</hi> and seems to be in a Peck of Fears, lest we <hi>should have
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:47428:12"/>occasion for their Assistance, and be deny'd it;</hi> but by what Logick he will make it In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gratitude, I can't imagine; for if I employ Men to do a Job of Work, and I pay 'em when they have done, no fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther obligation lies upon me. Souldiery is now become a Trade, and the State em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploying them as Mercenary Journey-men, for a Week, a Year, or longer, may discharge those Stipenda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, when they have no further occasion for their Service; which our <hi>Remar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker,</hi> and the rest of his Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitrary Upholders, may take for his Answer, unless he will have it in the Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sures of a late true <hi>English</hi> Poet.</p>
            <q>
               <l>'Tis true w'ave sent away the <hi>Dutch,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Those mighty Son's of Slaughter,</l>
               <l>And <hi>England</hi> ought to wish all such,</l>
               <l>As at their marching off think much;</l>
               <l>Were forc'd to follow after.</l>
               <l>The <hi>Hogan</hi> Troops dishonour'd thus,</l>
               <l>As your Invective shews it,</l>
               <l>In sorry Rags without a Sons,</l>
               <l>Came to relieve themselves, not us,</l>
               <l>And all the Kingdom knows it.</l>
            </q>
            <pb n="21" facs="tcp:47428:12"/>
            <p> Nor, If an Invasion should happen, is there so much danger, as is preten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded; for as <hi>English</hi> Men know the benefit of their Liberties, so will they ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture as freely for them; es<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecially when what they defend is not only their own, but the just Rights of all Mankind, and will preserve their Posterity from being <hi>Puppy-Dogs,</hi> when they fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the Eternal Counsel of God, as <hi>Zuinglius</hi> calls it. <hi>If thou maist be Free, use it ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther,</hi> and seek only to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue his Servants, and their own Men, this entitles them to a higher assistance: For <hi>omnibus honestam Libertatem quaerentibus</hi> (and which is a better <hi>propugnantibus) Deus proesto est:</hi> And God him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self will own such a cause as this.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>